{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Angola","incorrectAnswers":["Mauritius","Ethiopia","Morocco"],"question":"Where would you find the city of Luanda?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Almonds ","incorrectAnswers":["Pistachios","Hazelnuts","Walnuts"],"question":"What kind of nuts are used in marzipan?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Non ducor, duco","incorrectAnswers":["Fons vitae caritas","Pax vobiscum","Sequere pecuniam"],"question":"Which of these Latin phrases translates to 'I am not led, I lead'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"John Grisham","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen King","J.K. Rowling","Dan Brown"],"question":"Which author had a No. 1 bestseller in 2015 with his latest legal thriller 'Rogue Lawyer'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"You're So Vain\" by Carly Simon","incorrectAnswers":["\"SpongeBob SquarePants Theme\" by Painty the Pirate","\"What I Got\" by Sublime","\"Old Man\" by Neil Young"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"You walked into the party like you were walking onto a yacht.\"?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"White","incorrectAnswers":["Orange","Green","Maroon"],"question":"Which of these colors is included on the flag of Malta?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Little Jack Horner","incorrectAnswers":["Humpty Dumpty","Jack","Happy Hungry Harry"],"question":"According to the nursery rhyme, who, 'sat in the corner eating a Christmas Pie''?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Khao Soi","incorrectAnswers":["Toad in the Hole","Kentucky Fried Chicken","Chicken Tikka Masala"],"question":"Which of these dishes is most commonly found in Northern regions of Thailand?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Aaron Sorkin","incorrectAnswers":["David Chase","Joss Whedon","Matthew Weiner"],"question":"Which writer created the television series 'The West Wing'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Antwerp","incorrectAnswers":["Rome","Paris","Oslo"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Belgium?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Corona","incorrectAnswers":["Arendelle","Belgravia","Aldova"],"question":"What is the name of the kingdom Rapunzel is from in Disney's 2010 film Tangled?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Saltpetre","incorrectAnswers":["Borax","Limestone","Quartz"],"question":"What is the common name for potassium nitrate?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Bunny","incorrectAnswers":["An Elver","A Farrow","A Tadpole"],"question":"What is the word for a young rabbit?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Jack London","incorrectAnswers":["Edgar Rice Burroughs","James Fenimore Cooper","Frederik Pohl"],"question":"Which author wrote 'White Fang'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Zulu","incorrectAnswers":["Zebra","Zoological","Zipper"],"question":"What word is used in the NATO Phonetic Alphabet for the letter Z?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Grommet","incorrectAnswers":["Winklepicker","Curmudgeon","Cattywampus"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'an eyelet of firm material to strengthen or protect an opening or to insulate or protect something passed through it'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Agent Phil Coulson","incorrectAnswers":["Wong","Dr. Bruce Banner","Nick Fury"],"question":"In the Marvel Cinematic Universe, which character is played by Clark Gregg?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Myanmar","incorrectAnswers":["Tajikistan","Kyrgyzstan","Thailand"],"question":"Which of these countries borders India?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"China","incorrectAnswers":["Indonesia","The USA","India"],"question":"In which country would you find the Leshan Giant Buddha, the largest and tallest stone Buddha statue in the world?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Italy","incorrectAnswers":["Germany","United States","England"],"question":"Which country hosted the 1934 FIFA World Cup?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Lawrence of Arabia","incorrectAnswers":["City Lights","Sunset Blvd.","Braveheart"],"question":"Name the movie that matches the following plot summary: 'The story an English officer who successfully united and led the Arab tribes during World War I.'","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"A cosmopolitan","incorrectAnswers":["A martini","A mojito","A margarita"],"question":"Which cocktail contains vodka, cranberry juice, lime juice, triple sec, and an orange twist?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Bohemia","incorrectAnswers":["Prussia","Silesia","Moravia"],"question":"From the Christmas Carol \"Good King Wenceslas\", where was Good King Wenceslas the King of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The 5 Continents","incorrectAnswers":["The 5 founding countries of the modern Olympics","The 5 city states of ancient Greece","The 5 events of the ancient Olympics"],"question":"What do the five rings on the Olympic flag represent?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A nye","incorrectAnswers":["A sedge","A parliament","A clowder"],"question":"What is the word for a group of pheasants?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Luc Besson","incorrectAnswers":["Steven Spielberg","Woody Allen","Martin Scorsese"],"question":"Which director directed Lucy?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Denmark ","incorrectAnswers":["Sudan","Hungary","Japan"],"question":"The Airline Danair Is Based Where?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Romanov","incorrectAnswers":["Nikolevsky","Napoleon","Lenin"],"question":"What was the name of the reigning imperial house of Russia from the 17th century until the 1917 revolution?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Tonic Water ","incorrectAnswers":["Lemonade","Rum","Cream Soda"],"question":"Which drink was created when Indian army officers added quinine to soda water to help fight malaria?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"The Saints","incorrectAnswers":["The Bees","The Clarets","The Citizens"],"question":"What is the nickname of the English football team Southampton?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Inflation","incorrectAnswers":["GDP","Profit Margin","Unemployment Rate"],"question":"What is the term for the rate at which the prices of goods and services increase over time?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Black","incorrectAnswers":["White","Green","Gold"],"question":"Which of these colors is included on the flag of Albania?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Chemist and physicist who ade contributions to atomic theory.","incorrectAnswers":["Industrialist who revolutionised mass-production techniques.","Confirmed the theory that Earth revolves around The Sun.","38th President of the US."],"question":"Which of the following describes John Dalton?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Annual","incorrectAnswers":["Perennial","Evergreen","Ephemeral"],"question":"What Name Is Given To A Plant That Grows From Seed & flowers And Dies Within A Year? ","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Michael Douglas","incorrectAnswers":["William Hurt","Marcello Mastroianni","Jack Nicholson"],"question":"Who won the 1987 Academy Award for Best Leading Actor for playing the role of Gordon Gekko in Wall Street?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Rhombus","incorrectAnswers":["Triangle","Pentagram","Trapezoid"],"question":"Which of these shapes has four sides of equal length?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Nuku'alofa","incorrectAnswers":["Dhaka","Vaduz","Saint George's"],"question":"What is the capital city of Tonga?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Volkswagen","incorrectAnswers":["Aston Martin","Bugatti","Audi"],"question":"Which car manufacturer makes the Passat?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Qatar","incorrectAnswers":["Lebanon","Bahrain","Egypt"],"question":"Where would you find the city of Doha?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Novocaine","incorrectAnswers":["Lidocaine","Cocaine","Morphine"],"question":"In 1905, German scientist Alfred Einhorn created the first injectable local anesthetic used in dentistry. What is it called?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Ursa Major","incorrectAnswers":["Canis Major","Cygnus Major","Leo Major"],"question":"What is the name of the constellation that is commonly known as 'Big Bear'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"Bond. James Bond.\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"What we've got here is failure to communicate.\"","\"Sawyer, you're going out a youngster, but you've t to come back a star!\"","\"Well, I don’t want to survive. I want to live.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film 'Dr. No'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Argentina","incorrectAnswers":["Brazil","England","West Germany"],"question":"Which country won the 1978 FIFA World Cup, hosted in Argentina?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Taipei","incorrectAnswers":["Adelaide","Fukuoka","Brisbane"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Taiwan?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Michael Jackson","incorrectAnswers":["Nicki Minaj","Neil Young","Eric Clapton"],"question":"Which American singer, songwriter and dancer released the song 'The Way You Make Me Feel'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Doe","incorrectAnswers":["A Tigeress","A Leopardess","A Cow"],"question":"What is the word for a female kangaroo?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Ratoon","incorrectAnswers":["Curmudgeon","Tittynope","Fudgel"],"question":"Which word is defined as 'a small shoot growing from the root of a plant'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Due","incorrectAnswers":["Earned","Needed","Appreciated"],"question":"Complete this popular saying: 'Give credit where credit is _______'","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"GoodFellas","incorrectAnswers":["The Searchers","The Shining","The Treasure of the Sierra Madre"],"question":"Which film contains the character 'Tommy DeVito'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Kirsten Dunst","incorrectAnswers":["Charlize Theron","Emma Thompson","Helen Mirren"],"question":"Which actress has had roles in films including Fargo and Spider-Man?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Rococco","incorrectAnswers":["Baroque","Neoclassical","Gothic"],"question":"Which architectural style employed refined, elegant, highly decorative forms?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"iPod","incorrectAnswers":["PlayStation","Blackberry","Game Boy"],"question":"What device had a model called the 'Nano' released in 2005?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Phaser","incorrectAnswers":["Lightsaber","Blaster","Pulse rifle"],"question":"On Star Trek, what was the main weapon used by the crew of the USS Enterprise?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Catherine the Great","incorrectAnswers":["Catherine the First","Mary the 1st","Elizabeth the First"],"question":"Which Russian Empress came to power after overthrowing her husband?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Keanu Reeves","incorrectAnswers":["Christian Bale","Gérard Depardieu","Shah Rukh Khan"],"question":"Which actor has starred in films including The Matrix and Bram Stoker's Dracula?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Belgium","incorrectAnswers":["Italy","Bosnia & Herzegovina","Brazil"],"question":"In which country would you find the city of Bruges?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Oaked","incorrectAnswers":["Furten","Barrel-aged","Woody"],"question":"What term is used to describe a wine that is aged in oak barrels?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Hors d'oeuvres","incorrectAnswers":["À la carte","Croquettes","Tapas"],"question":"What is the French term for appetizers that are served before the meal?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"The moon","incorrectAnswers":["Tax","Heat","Interactions between siblings"],"question":"What is Selenology the study of?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Japan","incorrectAnswers":["Indonesia","China","South Korea"],"question":"In which country would you find Mount Fuji?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"Cambodia","incorrectAnswers":["Taiwan","Spain","Belgium"],"question":"In which country is sombai a popular drink?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Ferdinand Magellan ","incorrectAnswers":["King Charles II","Napoleon","Francis Drake"],"question":"Who renamed the South Sea as the Pacific Ocean in 1520?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Roy Orbison","incorrectAnswers":["Elvis Presley","Bill Haley","Jerry Lee Lewis"],"question":"Whose First Record Was A Rocker Called \"Ooby Dooby\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Washington, D.C.","incorrectAnswers":["New York City","Los Angeles","Chicago"],"question":"In 2002, which US city saw a number of coordinated sniper killings?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"The Bubonic Plague","incorrectAnswers":["The Spanish Flu","Smallpox","Cholera"],"question":"Which epidemic hit London in the 17th century, killing tens of thousands of people each time?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"San Andreas fault","incorrectAnswers":["Magellan fault","Desperado fault","El Mariachi fault"],"question":"What is the main tectonic fault line in California?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A Spiderling","incorrectAnswers":["A Joey","A Leveret","A Codling"],"question":"What is a baby spider known as?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"Blue","incorrectAnswers":["Yellow","Purple","Red"],"question":"What colour is a robin's egg?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Surrealism","incorrectAnswers":["Abstraction","Pointilism","Cubism"],"question":"With what art movement was Salvador Dali associated?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"\"Bullet with Butterfly Wings\" by The Smashing Pumpkins","incorrectAnswers":["\"Jumpin', Jumpin'\" by Destiny's Child","\"All Along the Watchtower\" by Bob Dylan","\"Swing Life Away\" by Rise Against"],"question":"Which song begins with the lyrics: \"The world is a vampire...\"?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"science","correctAnswer":"A cete","incorrectAnswers":["A murmuration","A yoke","An unkindness"],"question":"What is the word for a group of badgers?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"St Petersburg","incorrectAnswers":["Paris","Athens","Rome"],"question":"Which of these cities is in Russia?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Abbreviate","incorrectAnswers":["Abolish","Abduct","Abhor"],"question":"What is the verb that means to shorten a word or phrase by omitting letters?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"William Shakespeare","incorrectAnswers":["Arthur C. Clarke","Isaac Newton","Enid Blyton"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Romeo and Juliet'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Murder on the Orient Express","incorrectAnswers":["Death on the Nile","The Flying Scotsman","Pain on Blain the Train"],"question":"In which Agatha Christie novel does coroner Dr. Constantine help Poirot gather evidence on a train?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Etna","incorrectAnswers":["Merapi","Fuji","St Helen's"],"question":"What volcano showers ash on Sicily?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Zeus","incorrectAnswers":["Hercules","Ares","Hades"],"question":"Who is the Greek equivalent of the roman god Jupiter?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Porto-Novo","incorrectAnswers":["Ashgabat","Amman","Lusaka"],"question":"What is the capital city of Benin?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Rig Veda","incorrectAnswers":["Big Veda","Trig Veda","Gig Veda"],"question":"What is the 1st book of the Hindu scripture?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Morgan Freeman","incorrectAnswers":["Christopher Lee","Liam Neeson","Arnold Schwarzenegger"],"question":"Which actor played the role of Lucius Fox in Christopher Nolan's Batman trilogy?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Greenland","incorrectAnswers":["Madagascar","Borneo","New Guinea"],"question":"What is the largest island in the world? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Princess Margaret","incorrectAnswers":["Prince Charles","Elizabeth","James III"],"question":"After Henry VIII, Who Was The Next Member Of British Royalty To Get Divorced?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"Zoe Saldana","incorrectAnswers":["Catherine Deneuve","Audrey Hepburn","Rachel Weisz"],"question":"Which actress has played the roles of Gamora in the Marvel Cinematic Universe, and of Neytiri in the Avatar films?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Inky, Pinky, Blinky & Clyde","incorrectAnswers":["Inky, Pinky, Blinky & Floyd","Dinky, Pinky, Winky & Clyde","Dinky, Pinky, Blinky & Floyd"],"question":"What Are The Names Of The Ghosts In The Classic 80's Video Game Pac Man? ","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"food_and_drink","correctAnswer":"The Middle East","incorrectAnswers":["Europe","Central America","Africa"],"question":"From which part of the world do plums originate?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Black Beauty","incorrectAnswers":["Lassie Come-Home","The Call of the Wild","Watership Down"],"question":"Which novel, intended to \"induce kindness, sympathy and an understanding treatment of horses\", was written by Anna Sewell?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"The Rolling Stones","incorrectAnswers":["McFly","Delirious?","Depeche Mode"],"question":"Which English rock band released the song 'Sympathy for the Devil'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Sweden","incorrectAnswers":["Russia","Germany","Azerbaijan"],"question":"Stockholm is the capital city of which country?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Blue","incorrectAnswers":["Black","Green","Yellow"],"question":"Which of these colors is included on the flag of Greece?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"film_and_tv","correctAnswer":"\"This is Sparta!\"","incorrectAnswers":["\"Elementary, my dear Watson.\"","\"I have always depended on the kindness of strangers.\"","\"I love the smell of napalm in the morning.\""],"question":"Which of these quotes is from the film '300'?","difficulty":"easy"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Henry James","incorrectAnswers":["Edgar Allan Poe","Robert Louis Stevenson","Nathaniel Hawthorne"],"question":"Which author wrote 'The Turn of the Screw'?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"Atom Bombs","incorrectAnswers":["Race Horses","World War 2 Agents","Intel CPU Names"],"question":"What were 'Little Boy' and 'Fat Man'?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"general_knowledge","correctAnswer":"8","incorrectAnswers":["12","10","6"],"question":"How Many Furlongs Are There In A Mile?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"society_and_culture","correctAnswer":"Songs","incorrectAnswers":["Dances","Theatrical performances","Magic shows"],"question":"What does a \"casa de fado\" in Portugal usually feature in addition to food?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"music","correctAnswer":"Spice Girls","incorrectAnswers":["Pussycat Dolls","TLC","All Saints"],"question":"Which 90's girl group included Melanie C?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"sport_and_leisure","correctAnswer":"Detroit Tigers","incorrectAnswers":["Detroit Marlins","Detroit Trailblazers","Detroit Jaguars"],"question":"Which of these is a baseball team based in Detroit?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"geography","correctAnswer":"Ecuador","incorrectAnswers":["Brazil","Colombia","Chile"],"question":"In which country is the city of Guayaquil?","difficulty":"hard"},{"category":"history","correctAnswer":"Salem","incorrectAnswers":["Greensboro","Alexandria","Wilmington"],"question":"In which Massachusetts town were 20 people executed for witchcraft in 1692?","difficulty":"medium"},{"category":"arts_and_literature","correctAnswer":"Neil Gaiman","incorrectAnswers":["Stephen King","H. P. Lovecraft","Douglas Adams"],"question":"Which author wrote 'Smoke and Mirrors'?","difficulty":"hard"},